Guide to the Joseph Torchia papers M1694
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Joseph Torchia papers
circa 1970-1996
M1694
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
50.0 linear feet circa 50 linear feet
Manuscripts of published and unpublished works, research files for newspaper and magazine articles, journals and diaries, personal and professional correspondence, artwork, photographs, and ephemera.
Torchia, Joseph
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Jeff Adams to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2009.
Biographical Note
Joseph Torchia was an American writer and photographer. As a novelist and reporter he was perhaps best known as the author of THE KRYPTONITE KID. After working in San Francisco as a reporter from 1976 to 1978, he moved to Napa where he owned a photography studio.
Scope and Contents
The Joseph Torchia papers are divided into seven series. The majority of correspondence in Series 1 is between Joseph Torchia and his cousin, Theresa Marinaro, 1977-1996. Series 2 contains the original manuscripts for his books, The Kryptonite Kid, As If After Sex, The Edible Variety, and various other manuscripts. Included in this series are his personal diaries. Series 3 contains materials related to his works, mostly newspaper clippings and reviews. Series 4 contains his personal artwork and sketchbooks. Series 5 contains audiocassettes and computer disks; the audiocassettes were sent between Joseph and Theresa Marinaro to accompany the correspondence. Series 6 contains tax and personal financial records of Joseph Torchia.
Adams, Jeff
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: Incoming Correspondence
    - Billy Abrahams (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Jeff (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adriano, Mario (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Steve Alexander (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Allen, Mark (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alo (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ambrose, Sandy (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Anstadt (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - As if after sex (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters (As if after sex) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Barbar (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Barron, Jane (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Raymond Becker (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Black, Jim (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bradford, Greg (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bridge (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bush, Ron (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Buster (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Carby, Norm (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bill Chapin (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Christo (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Clot, Jean-Yves (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Cohen, Leonard (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Crawford, Dave (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Darpel, Marc (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Darr, Bob (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dawidorff, Robert (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Torchia: Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Torchia: Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Torchia: Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Torchia: Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Incoming Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Claude [Beaupere?] 1964 to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Gilbert, Stewart (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Candy and Randy to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sarah Gordon incoming and ougoing Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Gunay Necati to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Jane Krivacek to Joseph Torchia 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - John Lugar (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Robert Marisa to Joseph Torchia 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Tim Meade to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - The Pipe Smoker's Ephemeris to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Kathy Reddaway to Joey Torchia 1984-96 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence regarding the Kryptonite Kid vs. Warner Communications (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Jude Riley to Joseph Torchia 1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Robert Rodriguez to Joseph Torchia 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Robert Rodriguez to Joseph Torchia 1982-84 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Robert Rodriguez to Joseph Torchia, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - San Francisco Chronicle letter to Joseph Torchia, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Kate Schlafly to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Schulz (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Shari Shink to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Shipman, Geo. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Mari Jon Short to Joseph Torchia (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Aaron Shurin (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Jim Simpler (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Chuck Simpson (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Dave Skilton (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Warren Smith (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Joe Starita, 1970-73 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Joe Starita, 1974-84 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Steinfield Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sydney to Joseph Torchia, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tatro, 1969-1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Tatro, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Randy Testa, 1983-1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Randy Testa, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Randy Testa to Joseph Torchia (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - J.A. Torchia (Joseph's mom), to Joseph Torchia 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Michael and Jeffrey Torchia to Joseph Torchia (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Nina Toumanoff to Joey Torchia (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Joe Starita Miscellaneous Material (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Vocke to Joey Torchia, 1971-1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Shelley & Mark Von Beulan (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Michael Williams to Joseph Torchia (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Wilson (World School), 1976 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Mr X" Greg (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Yornell Steve (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Zaltoon Sam to Joseph Torchia (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Steve Brown to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Becky Enneis to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Rusty Epps to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Fennelly David to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Tino Ferrante to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Bob Gilbert to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - D. Patrick Haley to Joseph Torchia, 1973-1975 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - D. Patrick Haley to Joseph Torchia, 1976-1981 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - D. Patrick Haley to Joseph Torchia, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Edie Hanes to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Dorothy Henriquez to Joseph Torchia, 1977-1979 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Robert "Chip" Hogan to Joseph Torchia, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Robert "Chip" Hogan to Joseph Torchia, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Robert "Chip" Hogan to Joseph Torchia, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Frank Holbrook to Joseph Torchia, 1974-1976 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Frank Holbrook to Joseph Torchia, 1977-1979 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Frank Holbrook to Joseph Torchia, 1980-1983 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Sally, Sue and Frank Holbrook to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - David Holliday to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - George R. Just to Joseph Torchia (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1995-1996 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1996 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1996 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1996 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1996 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fan mail: 1996 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - John G. Marini to Joseph Torchia (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Incoming Correspondence regarding the Kryptonite Kid 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Incoming Correspondence regarding the Kryptonite Kid 1980 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Incoming Correspondence regarding the Kryptonite Kid 1981 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Incoming Correspondence regarding the Kryptonite Kid 1983-1985 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Incoming Correspondence regarding the Kryptonite Kid undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: elementary school children to the character Jerry (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Incoming Correspondence Ms. Sunborg's 3rd grade class [1986] (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Student-Torchia Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Incoming Correspondence from students (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Incoming Correspondence from students (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Christmas cards from a class to Joseph Torchia (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Jamie Jobb to Joseph Torchia (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - William Carter-Spann (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 2: Outgoing Correspondence
    - Joseph Torchia to Charles Gravett (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Joey Torchia to Denny Haley, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Joey Torchia to Denny Haley, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Joey Torchia to D. Patrick Haley, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Torchia to D. Patrick Haley, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Joseph Torchia to D. Patrick Haley (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Joey Torchia to Robert "Chip" Hogan, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Joseph Torchia to Robert "Chip" Hogan 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Robert Hogan Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Joseph Torchia to P&K Reddaway (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Joseph Torchia to Walker Stewart, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Joseph Torchia to Walker Stewart, 1983-86 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Joseph Torchia to Walker Stewart, 1987-88 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Joseph Torchia to Walker Stewart, 1989-1995 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Joseph Torchia to Walker Stewart, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Joey Torchia to his family, letters from Turkey (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Torchia letters from Turkey 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Postcards to Mr. and Mrs. Jasper Torchia from Joseph Torchia (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Postcards to Theresa Ann from Joseph Torchia (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Postcards of Turkey (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Postcards and letters (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Postcards (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 3: Joseph Torchia/Theresa Marinaro correspondence
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Jan. - July 17,1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, July 18- Nov. 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Jan. - Apr. 6,1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Apr. 14 - Aug. 24,1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Aug. 28 - Dec. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Jan.- Jun. 6, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Jun. 13 - Dec. 1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Jan. - Mar. 23, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, Apr. 18 - Dec. 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph, Torchia 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Theresa Marinaro to Joseph Torchia, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Theresa Marinaro, outgoing (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Joey Torchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - JoeyTorchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - JoeyTorchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Joey Torchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Joey Torchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1984-85 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Joey Torchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Joey Torchia to Theresa Marinaro, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Joey Torchia [Ditto - The Cat] to Theresa Marinaro, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Joey Torchia to Theresa Marinaro, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence related to Cassette tapes, 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Series 2: Manuscripts/Writings/Diaries
  - "Dirty Book" Diary (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Dirty Book" Diary (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Artwork for Edible Variety? (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Edible Variety drafts (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Edible Variety drafts (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Edible Variety draft sent to Theresa Marinaro (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Edible Variety draft by Joseph Torchia (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Chapter one draft of the Edible Variety (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Chapter two draft of the Edible Variety (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chapter three draft of the Edible Variety (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Chapter four draft of the Edible Variety (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Inscribed typescript: The Edible Variety (Box 11, Folders 11-12)
  - Manuscript: The Edible Variety (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - The Edible Variety: The Sexual Exploits of a Snail, Joseph Torchia (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Inscribed Typescript: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Inscribed Typescript: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Kryptonite Kid Screenplay Adaptation by Ross H. Jones and Joseph Torchia, August 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Kryptonite Kid, Joseph Torchia (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - The Kryptonite Kid Original (1st draft) (Box 12, Folders 5-6)
  - The Kryptonite Kid by Joseph Torchia (Box 12, Folders 7-8)
  - Manuscript: The Kryptonite Kid by Joseph Torchia (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript: The Kryptonite Kid by: Joseph Torchia (Box 13, Folders 1-2)
  - Manuscript: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Kryptonite Kid Original Revision (2nd Final Draft) (Box 13, Folders 4-6)
  - "The Kryptonite Kid" (Final Xerox from N.Y.) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "The Kryptonite Kid" (Final Xerox from N.Y.) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript:The Kryptonite Kid by Joseph Torchia (Box 14, Folders 2-3)
  - Brown's Requiem Screenplay by Denise Iorio (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Drafts by Joesph Torchia (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Inscribed typescript: Sophomore (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - The Crucifixion, a story by Joe Torchia (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Milton at the movies by Rany-Michael Testa (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Twilights of good fortune or "Fly Me", Joseph Torchia (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Purgatory, Pa. Synopsis Randy (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "Sex, Lies and Videotape", Screenplay by Steven Soderbergh (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "The Fabulous Baker Boys Steve Kloves, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Blue Velvet Original Screenplay David Lynch, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Original Typescript pages 2-103 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Original Typescript pages 104-212 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Original Typescript pages 213-310 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Original Typescript pages 311-411 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Inside Flannery O'Connor (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Inscribed typescript: Purgatory, PA. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Inscribed typescript: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Inscribed typescript: The Edible Variety (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Inscribed typescript: As if After Sex (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Inscribed typescript: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Fist Final Draft Read by Knopf + Doursleda (Box 17, Folders 1-3)
  - Torchia Notebook, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Torchia Notebook, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Torchia Notebook, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Torchia Notebook, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Torchia Notebook, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Torchia Notebooks, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Torchia Notebooks, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Torchia Notebooks, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Joseph's Notebooks regarding trip to Mexico, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 1995 Datebooks (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Kryptonite Kid: a play in five dimensions (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - The Full (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - John Widlock's Acting Workshop (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - The Beauty Mark (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Prok Chops and other people (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - The Fifth Dimension (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - As if after Sex (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - As if after Sex (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "The Kryptonite Kid" (original) (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts (D. Patrick Haley?) (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - D. Patrick Haley manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Utopia heights Screenplay by James Hart Jobb 1986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Inside Flannery O'Connor, by Joseph Torchia (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Inside Flannery O'Connor, by Joseph Torchia (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - The Photograph, by Joseph Torchia (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Graysmith Zodiac 234-315 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Various drafts (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Various drafts (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - A tale of two noses (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - "Completely West", early drsft, early title (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Akchakauk! (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Akchakauk! (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Editions de L'Amite', Editions de l'Amite' 21 Rue Cassette Paris 75006 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Exercises (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Eyes (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Fans (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Florida, U. of Florida (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - 40 Stanzas (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Fussman, Calvin (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Gay Sunshine (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - (Gavin, Steve) (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Word Work (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Tales of no wisdom, D. Patrick Haley (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Daily Activites, a novel by D. Patrick Haley (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Publications by Ron Jones (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - The Kryptonite Kid Galleys (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - As if after Sex first proof Galleys (Box 36, Folders 2-3)
  - As if after Sex first proof Galleys (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - As if after Sex Page proofs (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - The Edible Variety Manuscript (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Corrected Galley Proof: The Kryptonite Kid (Box 37, Folders 1-2)
  - The Kryptonite Kid: MAster Copy of Scene breakdown (pp. 1-99) (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - The Kryptonite Kid: Master Copy of Scene Breakdown, pp. 100-215 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - The Kryptonite Kid - movie rights; play (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - The Kryptonite Kid (scene breakdown), pp. 1-109 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - The Kryptonite Kid (scene breakdown), pp. 110-215 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - The Kryptonite Kid: Screenplay by John Lugar + Joseph Torchia (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Reviews: As if After Sex (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Torchia Diary: From the Attic to the Garden (Box 38, Folders 3-4)
  - Torchia Diary: Jan. 4, 1980 - June 27,1984 (Box 38, Folders 5-7)
  - Joseph Torchia's journal (computer printout) (Box 38, Folders 8-9)
  - Scroll: unknown manuscript (Box 42)
  - The Kryptonite Kid (Carton 47, Folders 1-3)
  - As if After Sex, manuscript by Joseph Torchia (Carton 47, Folders 4-6)
  - The Edible Variety manuscript, by Joseph Torchia (Carton 47, Folders 7-9)
  - The Kryptonite Kid manuscript (Carton 47, Folders 10-11)
  - The Kryptonite Kid manuscript (Carton 47, Folders 12-14)
  - The Edible Variety manuscript (Carton 47, Folders 15-16)
  - The Edible Variety and other Tales manuscript (Carton 47, Folders 17-18)
  - "The Edible Variety" Journal (Carton 47, Folder 19)
- Series 3: Biographical/Ephemera
  - Acting Class (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Birth Certificate (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chronicle (Ruth Miller's Notes Letters of Resignation Telephone Directory ETC...) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Computer (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Performances (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - California State College ephemera (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - High School ephemera (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Alligator (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - EFS- Eureka Federal Savings (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Empty Envelopes (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Creative Writing Program (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Turkey Pamphlets (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: Rathbun Harry (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Roadster (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: Rocky Horror (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Clippings: Roccer Skating in G.G. Park (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: Rotary (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Clippings: RV Craze (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Scuba (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: Sea Scouts (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: S.F. Sex Hotline (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: Sex Link (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: Smugglers (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: Soccer Coach (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Clippings: Somogi Judith (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Superman (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: Glen Taylor (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: What's it like to be a tourist...San Francisco (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: Tourists (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Traveler's aid (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Clipping: Turkeys (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Clipping: Ups (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Clipping: Vans (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Clipping: Vasilik (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Clipping: Water Witcher (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Clipping: Watergate (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Clipping: Vivian Younger (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Clipping (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Tullah (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Forces of Middle East, Joseph Torchia (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Torchia's Stories, poems from Turkey (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - St. Martin's Press (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Magazines of Turkey (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Wolfe Tom (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Wordsworths (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Zak (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Joseph Torchia, "Akchakauak" (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Index to tape recordings (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets of Turkey (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets of Turkey (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Japanese (Award?) (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Sonoma Valley Wine Auct. 1996 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Medi-Cal Etc. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Medical Appointments (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - San Francisco General Hospital (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Notes about Robert's Death (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Resume (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Robert Roper Clipping (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Rubber Stamps (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Publishers Weekly July 23, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Sheski Steve and Russell Scott (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - North West October 1979 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Holt Rinehart & Winston 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Columbia House (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Writer's Group (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Eyes (Glasses) (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Supplemental Security Income (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Project Inform (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Chemotherapy (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Holt Rinehart & Winston (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - N. Valley 1996 Wine Auction (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - To be answered (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Archyology - The Long lost Tales of archy and mehitabel (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Paul C. Buff (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Jean-Yves Clot (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - California Living Magazine (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - California Living Magazine (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - J. Galucci Painting circa 1980 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Escargots from your garden to your table, Francois Picart (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Flannery O'Connor Bulletin (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Sex Link, Hy Freedman (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - La Cancha Newsletter Material (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Story (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Newsclippings and Pamphlets (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - La Cancha Newsletter (Box 23, Folder 4)